# Shane Smith

# Experience

### Web and Mobile Developer, MediaShane

2014 - Present

• Use modern web technologies and methods to build responsive web and mobile applications

### Englisher Teacher, Prince Royal's College and Upgrade Academy

2014 - 2015 | Thailand

Teach English to children and adults of all ages in both large and small classroom environments

### Web Developer / Associate Producer, KUED Channel 7

2013 - 2014 | SLC, UT

- Develop the official kued.org website and produce associated digital content
- Research and produce short form documentaries on local social issues

### Visual Literacy Image Curator, Marriott Library

2013 | SLC, UT

Design, layout and install a vocabulary of symbols to represent the Library of Congress classifications

### Web Developer / Digital Media Specialist, SLCPL

2009 - 2012 | SLC, UT

- Lead administrator and developer of all things digital (slcpl.org, intranet, social networks, media content, etc.)
- Research and implement new technology trainings, services and programs

### Librarian, Salt Lake City Public Library

2007 -2009 | SLC, UT

• Served patrons as a circulation and reference librarian

### Web Developer, Red Butte Garden

2009 | SLC, UT

Developed and maintained the official redbuttegarden.org

#### Database Administrator, Utah Museum of Fine Arts

2004 - 2005 | SLC, UT

Administered fund-raising and membership database

# Skills

### Frameworks / Languages

- React + Redux
- React Native
- Node + Express
- Angular
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Ruby + Rails
- PHP
- HTML5
- CSS3 + SASS
- WordPress
- Drupal

#### Frontend Frameworks

- Bootstrap
- Material Design
- Semantic UI
- Ionic / Cordova

#### **Productivity**

- Git + Github
- Slack
- JIRA
- Gulp

#### Creative

- Premiere Pro
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign

#### **Databases**

- Relational (SQL, PostgreSQL)
- Non-relational (NoSQL, Mongo, Couch)

# Education

B.A. in English, University of Utah CELTA Certification

# References

Mark Thomas, Web Master, KUED 7 801-750-6826. mthomas@kued.org

Jon Davies, Director of Interactive Media, KUED 7 801-581-5506, jdavie@kued.org

Mary Dickson, Creative Services Director, KUED 7 801-581-3263, mdickson@kued.org

# Profile

I love to make stuff. Responsive sites, mobile apps, data toys, and software. Videos, music, photographs, and narratives. I build products and craft experiences to make people's lives better, either by solving a problem or fulfilling a need. Above all, I have an endless passion for learning and helping others.

I encourage you to visit mediashane.com to learn more.

## Contact

shane@mediashane.com 801-410-3048 1306 NE Ainsworth St. Portland, OR, 97211 mediashane.com www.linkedin.com/in/mediashane https://github.com/mediashane